In this chapter, we'll dive into the LoRa-modulation.
We need to understand how the binary data are transmitted in the air, then we'll estimate the bitrate of transmission
first by using theoretical values from the datasheet and then practical value that we can really expect
in the field.
That will depend on parameters such as: the Spreading Factor, the Coding Rate, the Bandwidth, the
Time-On-Air and the Duty Cycle.
But of course, all these terms will be defined and explained in detail.
Then, we'll simulate a LoRa packet transmission with a software called LoRa Calculator, and this will
allow us to confirm the previous results.
Finally, we'll learn how to estimate the power consumption of LoRa device.
This consumption.
So the autonomy of the device depends on several transmission parameters.
Once again, for this explanation we will see this through an example.